KEVIN JEFFERS WEB PRODUCER

kevinjeffers.me | linkedin.com/in/kevin-jeffers | github.com/jevinkeffers | newspagedesigner.org/members/KevinJeffers

CONTACT

404-956-0575 kevinjeffers2@gmail.com

Based in Atlanta, Ga., but open to remote employment or relocation for the right opportunity.

SKILLS

Proficient with:

- Content management
- User-focused design
- · Graphic design
- · Web production
- · Adobe Creative Suite
- HTML
- CSS
- · SEO standards
- UX writing and editing
- Video and audio production and editing

Some experience with:

- JavaScript
- Python
- WordPress
- Accessibility and 508 compliance
- · UI development
- React
- Figma
- · Node.js
- · Backend development
- · Database structures

More information and references available upon request.

ABOUT ME

Experienced professional with a proven knowledge of content management, publication, and web production. Creative and enthusiastic producer who focuses on user experience and has a keen eye for detail. Versatile skillset that includes web development with HTML and CSS, with the ambition to grow in JavaScript. Aiming to leverage my skills to deliver great user experiences for your products.

EXPERIENCE

Designer and Editor, Gannett; Remote — 2012-2013; 2019-Present

Currently in my second stint with Gannett, building, designing and producing newspaper pages as part of the Design Center and the USA Today Network. Duties include content management, design and editing.

Multimedia Journalist, The National; Abu Dhabi, UAE — 2014-2019

Headhunted among U.S.-based journalists to produce international sports and news content for a newsroom based in the Middle East. Served as a lead designer, sports editor, video and podcast producer. Led many projects, including the development an award-winning podcast network from scratch, user-testing and developing a new internal CMS, and leading a team of editors in the design and structure of the printed sports section.

Designer and Content Producer, Advance Publications, Mobile and Birmingham, Ala. — 2010-2012; 2013-2014

Two stints as a user-experience designer and content producer for the print and web products of The Birmingham News, Mobile Press-Register, and various other Advance-owned products. Helped develop SEO strategy at an integral time of transition for the Alabama newsroom operation.

Journalist, The Anniston Star; Anniston, Ala. — 2006-2010

While still in college, served many jobs for my local paper The Anniston Star, starting out reporting local high school sports and eventually being promoted to a full-time role as a copy editor and designer.

EDUCATION

Jacksonville State University; Jacksonville, Ala.

Bachelor of Arts with a major in Communications and minor in English, 2008 DigitalCrafts; Atlanta, Ga.

Certificate of Completion with a focus on web development and software engineering, 2020